

ANDREW MAINER

- P BENTONVILLE, AR
- armainer2014@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Retail professional with over 10 years of experience managing multi-billion-dollar portfolios and coordinating strategic initiatives across large variety of teams. Extremely strong pattern/process recognition ability with successful track record of building new businesses focused on profit maximization, cost minimization, and sustainable solutions. Excels in building teams up through teaching, training, and people development. Breadth of knowledge from working with multiple teams with nothing but exceeds expectations (and most recently **role model**) performance evaluations.

SKILLS

- Leadership/Team Building
- Big Data and Analytics
- Goal Setting/Prioritization
- Product Development
- Process Design/Improvement
- P&L Planning

- SQL, Python, & Data Science
- Task Automation
- KPI Development

NOTABLE ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Designed and executed beef upstreaming initiative resulting in Walmart owned end to end supply chain. Leveraged big data to identify and prioritize P&L opportunities across entire chain resulting in +\$29 million increase in profitability and -\$1 million reduction in waste.
- Created, built, and delivered end to end supply chain planning tool for beef upstreaming that connects and coordinates decisions made at the retail level and multiple manufacturing nodes. The tool currently services 10+ people and is scalable to other manufacturing facilities while focusing on live animal forecasting, raw need minimization, raw need balancing, and constraint optimization. This successfully delivers goals of maintaining target inventory of 12 days of supply (10-17 range) while also accurately forecasting raw need 5 weeks in advance (and live animal 2 years in advance), has its own truck load optimization, and provides load smoothing for 60 outbound trucks/week.
- Introduced the ability to scale cost optimization solutions at corporate level where work was being done at desk level. Favorite achievements include economic order quantity (EOQ) optimization at store level that drove +7% in sales, -2% in inventory, and had a 41% reduction in picks at DC and store and lost sales analysis and holiday flow optimization which drove +10% revenue and ensured product got to store during capacity constrained periods such as Thanksgiving/Christmas

Experience

Walmart Bentonville, Arkansas

Senior Merchant, Manufacturing – Meat and Seafood

Jan 2020 –Current

- Deliver +30 million/year profitability improvement through new sales channels and creative purchasing.
- Reduce and manage outstanding inventory balance to less than 2 DOS
- Successfully kept inventory within 10-17 day constraint with 12 day target and -\$1 million reduction in waste
- Primary product/tech owner for Creekstone relationship with a focus on continuous improvement and process engineering
- Create and define future of program through P&L prioritization, organizational structure, and tech strategy
- Develop and realize other's ideas through leadership, mentoring, and coaching

ANDREW MAINER

armainer2014@gmail.com

Senior Manager II, Beef Strategy – Meat and Seafood

Oct 2018 -Dec 2019

- Designed and execute strategic vision for upstreaming "startup" (Red Kingfisher, LLC) through multiple iterations of process creation and improvement. Primarily responsible for end-to-end supply chain design, flow, and business analytics
- Enabled P&L improvement by developing, tracking, and dashboarding KPIs and holding teams accountable to improvement
- Led and set vision for strategic partnerships through weekly internal and external presentations to garner buy in for program
- Coordinated with external CEO/COO/CFO partners as well internal cross functional teams (tech, finance, accounting, business) to setup first, second, and final iterations of process implementation to deliver upstreaming goals
- Oversaw the development of end-to-end supply chain planning tool used by all counterparts accomplished by coordinating with end users and leading a team of data scientists
- Mentored, trained, and developed new associates. Created and defined roles and responsibilities of each member on the team.

Senior Manager, Replenishment – Dry Grocery

Jun 2017 -Oct 2018

- Managed Desserts and Ingredients (Baking Mixes, Baking Nuts Canned Milk, Pie Filling, Syrups and Mixes).
- Drove inventory management wins on Bake Center leading to flat inventory and +13% sales.
- Led cross functional groups that drove sustainable and scalable solutions (i.e.: TLO optimization, EOQ strategies, SQL training, and COGs Excellence).
- Developed and coded logic for EOQ strategy that drove 7% in sales, -2% in inventory, and a 41% pick reduction at DC/Store

Manager, Replenishment – Dry Grocery

Jan 2017 -Jun 2017

- Managed a complex desk efficiently and effectively -- Baking Commodities Sugar, Flour, Oil, and Jell-o/Marsh
- Championed new ways of working during rollout. Supported centralization structure (DM & SSM).
- · Captured quick wins via lost sales automation, constraint optimization changes, and plan analysis budget projections
- Lost sales automation drove +10% in revenue and helped flow Thanksgiving/Christmas holiday volume under DC capacity
- Developed automation process for replenishment tasks including remedies, date changes, and PO maintenance

Replenishment Manager II – Dairy

Nov 2014 -Jan 2017

- Managed a variety of desks across Dairy, including Cultured, Hispanic Cheese, Juice, and Eggs
- Developed SQL/Automation to support team needs and initiatives
- Helped spread business ideas from other areas of company to improve overall performance (GRS Innovation)
- Drove supplier improvement by leading replenishment supplier summits for both Eggs and Dairy

EDUCATION

University of Arkansas

Fayetteville, Arkansas

M.B.A., GPA 3.9
Bachelor of Science in Civil Engineering, GPA 3.8 May 2012

CERTIFICATIONS

Discrete Optimization Online

Discrete Optimization certificate – built scalable solvers for projects such as knapsack/scheduling Used skills learned for RKF projects such as carrier scheduling – reduction of \$2 million in cost

May 2022

May 2014

eCornell Online

Machine Learning Certificate (Linear Classifiers, Decision trees, Kernel Machines, Deep Learning, NN)

June 2021

Personal: built an automated trading bot with buy flags signaled by ML techniques –running daily on a raspberry pi Professional: built an item classifier based on text inputs AND built an event driven email automation tool

University of Arkansas Global Campus

Rogers, Arkansas

Backend Web Development (HTML, CSS, Javascript, MongoDB, NodeJS)

Dec 2017